odeo.com 2009-05-10

# Odeo: Search, Discover and Share Digital Media from Millions of Audio and Video Clips

#### Privacy and Data Policy for Odeo

Odeo respects and values the privacy of our visitors and members. This privacy policy covers how Odeo treats personal information collected and received. 

Last updated: April 1, 2008 

#### What This Privacy Policy Covers

This policy covers personal information including personally identifiable information about you like your name or email address. This Privacy Statement does not apply to the use of your Personal Information by third parties that Odeo does not own or control, or to individuals that Odeo does not control or manage. Note also that children under 13 are not permitted to use Odeo. Therefore, Odeo's privacy policy does not account for children's use of the site. 

#### Links to Other Sites

Odeo contains links to media and other websites that are not owned or controlled by Odeo. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of such other sites. Information Collection, Data Ownership and Use 

Registered users of Odeo own their personal information and data created as a result of using Odeo.com. Odeo.com and SonicMountain Inc. will retain a non-exclusive license for the duration of time the user maintains data at Odeo. In addition, for the duration of time users maintain data at Odeo, they grant all users a commercial, non-exclusive reuse license to their publicly accessible data, created through the use of Odeo, unless they choose options to limit the public distribution of their public data, such as "subscriptions", “favorites”, or "playlists". This data may be accessible by default via RSS feeds or search, as well as through other methods of public collection. 

Odeo will not share or sell your personal information, such as email addresses, to anyone without your authorization or consent, with the exception of those terms disclosed in this Privacy Statement. Users of Odeo can request at any time that their personal or public data be removed, and to the fullest extent possible, a user's data will be removed from the Odeo system. Exceptions might include data that has been depersonalized and aggregated (see following paragraph) or data that is contained in backup systems. 

Odeo will aggregate information about users of the site. "Aggregated Information" means information where personally identifying information is removed, and lots of visitor's and member's data is aggregated together to become statistical information for Odeo about how the site is used. Aggregated information that is not personally identifying for users is solely owned by Odeo and is used to improve our services. Statistical information may be shared with other parties. 

#### Surveys or Contests

Odeo may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you decide to participate, we will request certain Personal Information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice about whether or not to disclose your information. The requested information may include contact information (such as name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip code). 

This information will only be used internally to determine eligibility, notify contest winners, and to measure the success of our efforts. Publicly held contest winners may be labeled on the Odeo site in public ways through their usernames, ID's, aliases, or other representations. 

#### General Information

Odeo collects personal information upon registration. When you register we ask for your email address and certain optional information such as your name, birth date, gender, biographical information, instant message user names, personal websites and personal interests. Odeo automatically collects and records information from your browser, including your IP address, cookie, and the page you request. IP Addresses are disclosed by your browser as you view a web page. Your IP address may also stored when you register with Odeo. 

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. 

  * You might configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set.
  * Rejecting all cookies means you will not be able to use Odeo products or services requiring you to "sign in."
  * Odeo uses its own cookies for a number of purposes, including:
    * Accessing your information when you "sign in".
    * Preference tracking while you are using Odeo's services.
    * Displaying the most appropriate advertising, based on your interests and activity on Odeo.
    * Estimating and reporting our total audience size and traffic.
    * Conducting research to improve Odeo's content and services.
  * Other advertising companies may set and access their cookies on your computer. They are subject to their own privacy policies, not the Odeo policy. Advertisers or other entities do not have access to Odeo cookies.

#### Third Party Advertisers

Advertisements appearing on Odeo may be delivered by a third party. For information about advertisers on Odeo, please visit their websites through links provided at the advertisements on Odeo. 

#### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Odeo allows many activities for member that will result in revealing of some information about your activities to others, including visitors and members. For example, these activities might include editing a media record, posting a comment, making a playlist or sending a message. When you "write" something in Odeo, your Odeo username, ID, or alias that you are posting under will be visible to other users. If you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Odeo is not responsible for the messages you post or receive, either publicly or through the Odeo messaging system. 

Generally, Odeo will not share your personal information with other people or nonaffiliated companies without your consent except to provide products or services you've requested and in the following circumstances: 

  * Odeo may be required to disclose personally identifiable information under special circumstances, such as to comply with subpoenas, warrants, court orders or legal process or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. 
  * It may be necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities, including without limitation, fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Odeo's terms of use, or as otherwise permitted or required by law. 
  * We will transfer information about you if Odeo is acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, Odeo will notify you by email or by putting a prominent notice on the Odeo web site before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. Odeo may share demographic information with business partners. No personally identifiable information will ever be used without your permission. 

#### Choice/Opt-out

At any time, you can change your Odeo account information. You can delete your Odeo account from your account page or by emailing Customer Support at support@odeo.com. If you request deletion through email, Odeo will delete your information within 14 days. However, please note that some personal information may need to be maintained if it is for billing or required by law. Some employees will have access to our personal information, but this will be limited to those whose jobs are dependent on such information. 

#### Changes in this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Statement is a living document. Odeo may update this policy at any time for any reason. If we significantly change how we handle personal information, we will notify the primary email address specified in your Odeo account. We will also place a notice on our blog and on the Privacy page at Odeo.com/privacy. 

If you have questions or suggestions please contact us at feedback@Odeo.com.
